A whole new speed of hero.
Sonic the Hedgehog is a action, science fiction,
comedy film directed by Jeff Fowler.
Powered with incredible speed, Sonic The Hedgehog
embraces his new home on Earth.
That is, until Sonic sparks the attention of super-uncool evil genius Dr.
Now it’s super-villain vs.
super-sonic in an all-out race across the globe to stop Robotnik
from using Sonic’s unique power for world domination.
Sonic (voice), played by Ben Schwartz.
Tom Wachowski, played by James Marsden.
Maddie Wachowski, played by Tika Sumpter.
Dr. Robotnik, played by Jim Carrey.
Rachel, played by Natasha Rothwell.
Wade Whipple, played by Adam Pally.
Sonic the Hedgehog is a 2020 action-adventure comedy
film based on the Sonic video game series.
The first installment in the Sonic the Hedgehog film series, it was directed by Jeff Fowler (in his feature film directorial
debut), written by Pat Casey and Josh Miller, and stars Jim Carrey, Ben Schwartz, James Marsden, and Tika Sumpter.
Schwartz voices Sonic, a blue anthropomorphic hedgehog who can run at supersonic speeds, who
teams up with small town sheriff Tom Wachowski to stop the mad scientist Dr.
Robotnik from taking over the world.
Development for a Sonic film began in the 1990s but did not leave the planning
stage until Sony Pictures acquired the film rights in 2013.
Fowler was brought in to direct in 2016.
After Sony put the project in turnaround,
Paramount Pictures acquired it in 2017.
Most of the cast signed on by August 2018.
Principal photography took place between September and October that year in Vancouver
and on Vancouver Island, with a release date set for November 8, 2019.
Following the negative reaction to the first trailer, released that April, Paramount delayed the
film by three months to redesign Sonic to more resemble his look in the video games.
Sonic the Hedgehog premiered at the Paramount
Pictures studio lot on January 25, 2020.
It was theatrically released in the United States on February 14
and in Japan on June 26, and received mixed reviews.
It set the record for the biggest opening weekend for a video game film in the United States and Canada and grossed $320 million
worldwide, becoming the sixth highest-grossing film of 2020 and the highest-grossing video game film adaptation in North America.
The film was followed by Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2022), Sonic the Hedgehog
3 (2024) and a television miniseries, Knuckles (2024).
The film explores themes of friendship, video game, san
francisco, california, road trip, cop.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.